And so, good afternoon everybody. Um, I
am letting everyone in from the waiting
room. So, we'll give everybody just a
moment to come in from the waiting room
and there's a few other people joining
in. So, good afternoon everybody. Uh, as
people are coming on in, um, my name is
Dr. Dominick Zerlo and I am with the New
Mexico Department of Health. I'm the
director for the Center for Medical
Cannabis and psilocybin. And this is the
Training and Education Committee for the
Medical psilocybin Advisory Board. And
the chair for this meeting is Brenda
Burkhardt. And, um, and today I'm going
to be, uh, sitting back a little bit and
listening. And so, we do have some
information from the department as we
had, uh, mentioned in the previous
meeting where we were going to put
together a list of the competencies. And
Jorge Gonzales, who is our program
manager, will go through that today.
But, in the meantime, I will turn it
over to you, Brenda. And, uh, thank much
everybody for attending. And, uh, thank
you again, Brenda, for chairing the
meeting.
>> Oh, well, thank you, Dominick. I really
appreciate that. Thank you all for
coming today. Uh, yes, so we're going to
be going over, uh, the core competency
framework for the Medical psilocybin
Training and Education here in New
Mexico. And so, we have, um,
a few things that we're going to be
pulling up today and and talking about,
uh, because we want to make sure that
the things that we are working on
together, that they all, uh, come
together with all of the other committee
meetings that are, um,
uh,
getting gathering their information. So,
it is, um,
all cohesive, that we can build this
program together, you know, and having
your, um, input as the public come in
and and, you know, your comments, your
feedback, the criticism, uh, all are all
are welcome because we really need that
to um either put some things in there,
change the language, understand where uh
we want this program to go, make it
distinctly um
uh New Mexican for uh
cultural reasons, and also too uh we're
such a different state that we're um
also having things that
we need to feel comfortable with and
safe about the kinds of things that
we're proposing here in education and
training.
Now um I know that there are some things
that uh we need to um probably go over
um off the right off the bat. So, um
Jorge, did you want to bring up um any
of the documents? I don't care in any
order you want to bring it up.
>> Okay. I Yeah, I will I will start with
the material that uh the department has
has created to present to the the
committee to review. Um and I will do
that at this moment. So, I'll I'll talk
about that in just a second. So, hello
everyone. Good afternoon. Thank you for
being here. My name is Jorge Gonzalez.
I'm the Medical Psilocybin Program
Manager. And the programs team has put
together a couple of documents uh to
present to you, and I'll explain those
one by one. Um and so with that, uh I'll
share this first one. So, this first
one, you know, there's been uh
conversations uh
in several of the committees about
approved uh training programs in
Colorado and Oregon. And so we just went
onto their websites and collected that
information for you. And again, when
when after this meeting for a few days,
we'll we'll we'll have those posted onto
the website so everybody can review
that. But also uh we also put the
websites for where we picked those up
from Colorado and from the Oregon
website. Um so, as of uh
this was collected by us uh on May 21st.
So, please check their websites directly
cuz that may may change over time. So,
uh and and you'll the committees here
will will discuss
uh about
about the folks who have received
training for this and whether or not
they will be your recommendation will be
to accept them as as eligible for
permits.
Uh so, uh again, here's a a statement,
too. If an organization loses status
with Colorado or again, it will not be
accepted into Mexico. But, here is the
list. I just kind of want to I won't go
through them for you, but I'll just I'll
scroll them scroll through them for you
to take a look at.
And then, here are the ones for Oregon.
And again, like I said, if you're
if you're not able to catch all of them
right now during during the meeting,
then we'll have we also have those
uh posted
uh on the website.
Okay? Uh thank you for doing that.
>> That was
>> Thank you, Jorge. Thank you for uh
posting all of that. Uh yeah, it's a
it's a lot of material to go through,
but we want to
try to align ourselves with uh what
Colorado and Oregon is are doing because
they're the ones that first set set
all of this up, and we want to be able
to
um
uh not reinvent the wheel here. And uh
there's there's there's no no reason for
us to
make up a bunch of things that you know
that are going to be the same things.
So, um anything else did you want to do
uh bring up here um as far as
>> Yeah, not with not as far as the
education training centers, but I do
want to present the second document.
And I we can answer questions in a
second. I see there's a hand up. I just
wanted to get through both of these and
we'll we'll open it up whenever you're
ready Brenda for for questions, okay? So
I'll just go over the I'll just go over
the next one.
And
I will share that now.
See there we go.
Just clear my page. So
what we did the team again the program
team what we did is we went back and
looked at suggestions that were made by
attendees of the committees and board
members and presenters. So those three
committees that we we collected that
information from were from the training
education committee, end-of-life care
committee, and the patient qualification
and safety committee. So what we did is
just collected everything that folks
have suggested over the last several
months and just put this into a bulleted
document for you and the committee to
review again. So rather than having you
to go back there we were able to do that
for you. So [snorts]
um
as I said the purpose of training
education with the purpose of the
training education committee's framework
which is here. And then the competency
suggestions that were made and I won't
go through all of them but I'll just go
over the the headers for you Brenda.
>> Okay.
>> So the company suggestions were history
and cultural context, psilocybin
and then there's sub sub points folks
can look at. And then also pharmacology.
>> Could you just
make them the font a little bit bigger?
>> I sure will. Thank you for that.
>> I don't I could wear my glasses too.
>> I know thank thank you for pointing that
that's that's good for me to know.
Maybe just a little bit more. Okay,
there we go.
>> Yeah, that's it.
>> So so there we go with pharmacology and
then neuroscience
and psychology. So, there's the sub
bullets.
And then a mental health and spiritual
care applications.
And then we have safety planning
protocols, screening and risk awareness
and assessment. So, there were several
in here and we put all those together.
And I just want to remind folks that
this is over three different committees.
And so, we looked at some of that were
the same
and just combined it into one of these
headers here. So, some of those
suggestions as we look back were were
folks that said the same things over the
over the over the over the the several
committees. And so, that just goes to
show that many people are on the on the
same
>> [snorts]
>> thought process and and and
what we're looking to have as far as
competencies. So,
okay, and the next one, ethics, consent
and power dynamics.
And then psilocybin informed consent.
Which we saw was was different a
different suggestion by a
by the committee.
And then legal and regulatory overview.
This would be something we would could
include
was suggesting to include in the New
Mexico module, which we've we've
discussed as well.
And then safety equipment, basic
mandatory equipment on how to use
including the following.
And then facilitation and support.
And then integration support.
And then HIPAA patient privacy and
working with PHI.
And then we we also decided that we
would include something separate from
end-of-life care. And this was taken
from looking at some of the things Dr.
Larry Lehman had said and said, "The
end-of-life psychedelic care core
competencies would be developed as a
distinct and specialized set of
requirements complementing rather than
duplicating the competencies outlined in
most psychedelic care programs." This
separation ensures clarity of purpose
and supports a more comprehensive and
integrated training framework. So,
uh
I'll let folks take a look at this
while I scroll down.
Okay.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> And there you are, Brenda.
>> That looks That looks
really
what I had in mind because I had um
written up
um
also modules as well
>> Mhm.
>> just to see
what um what that would look like, too.
Um So, at this point, I think what we're
we're looking at here is actually
um
what is going to be
in the competencies of
what our scope of practice is.
So, what um I think the next thing we
could look at is um
it actually
the things that I have written up are
are are pretty redundant and it's I
mean, we could take a look at what I had
what I made up and
it it's it's pretty aligned with with
with the other committees that came
came came to a conclusion here and wrote
up in in this document. So,
if you want, you could bring up
let's see the
first ones. I guess it [clears throat]
was the competency one.
>> Okay. I do see Catherine's hand up. Do
you want
>> So, let's let Catherine Yeah,
let's see what Catherine has to say.
Catherine?
>> Unmute your mic, Catherine.
>> Hi there, everybody. Um
>> Hi, Catherine.
>> Hi. I just had two things. Um the and I
wasn't able to look at the curriculum in
detail, obviously. But I noticed that
like trauma-informed practices wasn't
listed anywhere and maybe it is, I just
didn't see it. I just want to make sure
that we are offering trauma-informed
because, you know, people that go
through these journeys,
sometimes they don't even expect a
trauma to come up, but it does. And I
think it's really important that guides
understand how to help people work
through trauma. That's that's like key.
Um so, I just wanted to say that. And
then the second thing I wanted to say
about the first document, the list of um
education institutions that would
qualify, um
I just want us to be really aware that
Oregon
doesn't allow any therapy whatsoever.